# ZEESHANZAFAR

# LARAVEL FULL STACK DEVELOPER

43-Y-6 Madina Town Faisalabad +92-301-3650612 zeeshanzafar922@gmail.com

### PROFILE SUMMARY

I am a Laravel Full Stack Developer with two years of experience developing scalable and performant web apps with PHP and the Laravel framework. I am a coding enthusiast that enjoys working together to create solid online solutions that fulfil the demands of customers and end-users. I am looking for a challenging job that will allow me to harness my knowledge and contribute to the organization's success.

## PROFESSIONAL SKILL

Attention to detail
Strong problem-solving skills
Time management and organizational skills
Ability to write clean and maintainable code
Ability to work independently or as part of a team
Continuous learning and professional development
Adaptability to new technologies and development environments

## TECHNICAL SKILL

Programming languages: PHP, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Frameworks: Laravel, Vue.js, jQuery, Bootstrap, TailwindCSS

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB

Tools: Git, Visual Studio Code, Phpstorm, Postman, ClickUp

# EDUCATION

# **BS Software Engineering**

2019 - 2023

The University of Faisalabad

While earning my BS in Software Engineering degree, I maintained a 3.4 CGPA. During my stay at the university, I was involved in a variety of extracurricular activities and served as the head of the programming society. These experiences enabled me to gain useful skills and form significant relationships with my peers.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

### **Laravel Developer**

Jan, 2023 - Continue

Softrix Technologies

- Collaborate with a team of developers to build and maintain a large-scale web application using Laravel, Javascript, and MySQL.
- Develop and implement new features and functionality, while also improving existing code.
- Write efficient and reusable code while adhering to industry best practices.
- Troubleshoot and debug issues to ensure optimal performance and user experience.
- Participate in Agile development process and daily stand-up meetings.
- Collaborated with project managers to ensure projects were completed on time and within budget.

# **Full Stack Developer**

Nov, 2021 - Dec, 2022

Almahir Hub

- Designed and developed responsive and intuitive user interfaces using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Bootstrap
- Built scalable and performant web applications using Laravel MVC framework
- Integrated RESTful APIs with front-end interfaces using Vue.js and jQuery
- Optimized and managed database systems using MySQL
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to deliver high-quality projects within deadlines
- Conducted code reviews and provided constructive feedback to team members

Web Instructor Oct, 2021 – Jan, 2023

StepUp IT Solutions

- Providing mentorship and guidance of the basics fundamentals of web development
- Create a positive learning environment that fosters student success
- Perform administrative tasks such as record-keeping, student registration, and course evaluations, as well as participating in faculty meetings and other institutional activities.

## **PROJECTS**

- Image-to-Text Converter
- Flip Coin
- Minecraft Color Codes
- QR Scanner
- Morse Code Converter
- System provides translation services
- Hostel Management System
- Academy Management System
- CyberSage